uh
let's you okay let's go back to the
sunlight room ready here we go
watch your breath
just a single object your
breath there only one thing in the world
is your
breath e
pict the
room small room on the side of a
mountain the sunlight pouring in softly
gold
sunlight golden
color e
out the window you can see Blue
Sky
Mountains cross the valley
come into the room bring your mind into
the room
and the golden sunlight
your teacher is in front of you knees to
knees you can feel the warmth of their
body
against the front of your
body then you both raise your eyes
and you look into each other's
side e
and just look at their
eyes just one thing that you're thinking
about just one thing that you're looking
at there's nothing
else in the
world no other places no other
thoughts just the one thing just looking
into their
face seeing their
eyes e
and uh feel this love coming from their
Earth relax into that love surrender to
that love don't think about anything
else just feel the love coming from
their eyes and
relax be contented without talking no
movement
silence contented with the
silence and take that as
sustenance
e e
surrender into their eyes relax don't
think of anything
else and feed feed from that
and slowly come out
then you're can open your
eye okay we're going to start the poster
so get your poster ready
it should be interesting in small
room uh try to get it to where you could
ride on it if you had to maybe you could
curl it up or something I don't know
[Applause]
you can make noise it's
okay we're going to be
working here at the bottom so if you
want to you can just get that part up
[Applause]
you're working at the bottom of the
picture
[Applause]
can anybody not get a poster who wants a
poster you okay
okay all right so we're going to start
here
uh where the monk has the the Monk's at
the bottom of the path
and I'll be referring to the
numbers can see handwritten
numbers one two 3 4 5 6
[Applause]
so number one
here under the Monk's
feet it says uh Sam jpa what's Sam
[Applause]
jpa it's the very first level right just
put put the mind on the object okay just
putting the mind on the object you've
got the instruct uh the translation is
below and we're talking about number one
down it's called setting the mind on the
object uh in the instructions
below you'll see a number one in
Brackets followed by a one with a half
parenthesis around
it that number the second number refers
to the the the which number level it is
okay so the second number is telling you
that you're at level number one
and we translated it here as setting the
mind on the
object so uh the monk is just starting
out uh the meditation and they're just
setting the mind on the object
right
uh how
many how many cooks in the path if you
include the beginning and the end of the
path how many bends in the road
oh now you're rolling again anyway
roughly it's supposed to be that the
bends in the path roughly correspond to
the nine levels okay but not
exactly I think he throws in two two at
some places all right one is
here uh two is is here Tre is
here okay and it goes like that
Forest
[Applause]
uh so he's at Sam J uh does it have NEPA
does it have stting on the
object some tiny like do flies stay on
cowp briefly okay tiny tiny little
Landings on the hter okay what do you
call that air care and touch and go yeah
touch and
go he got some award for doing touch and
go so you know uh so just touch and go
on that you know and then
uh he's getting ready uh two different
weapons as you see in his hands there
are two different
uh instruments I should call them
perhaps uh he's going to try to
tame this elephant and this
monkey all right which you can guess
what they might refer
to uh in Ancient India when you uh try
to tame an elephant uh you need two
different instruments okay uh I forgot
they call mahot I think in India a
mahoot an an elephant trainer I I hear
they bond with the elephant like you you
have one elephant for many years and
they only respond to one mahoot you know
so then they they allow that through
many years of training they they allow
that person to ride on their back and uh
you need if you're a mahoot you need two
different instruments okay in his
uh left hand
you can see a a hook with a chain okay
so I'm going to call it the chain all
right can see a a hook with a chain
there must be some word for it I don't
know but
uh that one's used to draw the elephant
back so when the elephant gets out of
control a little bit or goes too far or
wanders off then that's a chain that you
used to pull the elephant back
okay in his left hand with a little hook
on the end of it okay that's I'm going
to refer to it as the
chain uh chain inbet is called chambas
say TBA TBA is uh I think how we
translate it down here I think it's Rec
did we translate it
yeah oh bringing the Mind back to the
object okay you can call it recollection
sometimes you can call it bringing the
Mind back to the object so the OB the
chain in his left hand
represents uh bringing the Mind back to
the object which implies
what that it left okay okay so Gamba or
recollection you can call it
recollection is
required uh to bring the Mind back to
the object once it has lost the
op so we
had
nine levels yes we have
six Powers we have four
states of mind but I didn't tell you
about the five and the
eight okay there's a five and an eight
also by the by the end of the week
you're going to have to know these five
different sets these five different
groups okay nine
levels six
Powers four states of
Mind five problems problems of
meditation five
classical problems of meditation
everyone who ever tries to meditate goes
through these five problems
okay uh so you're going to have to know
the five problems and then there are
eight corre Corrections or antidotes to
the five problems so you're going to
have to know a nine a six a four a five
eight by the time we're
done by the time we're done you should
have those in your mind you know you
should be able
to I want you to know them backwards and
forwards okay in theory you just these
are when Ken rache Learned to
Drive which was a three-year traumatic
experience for both of
us uh he had never ridden a bik he had
never seen a car till he was like
uh anyway it was pretty scary uh the rib
test was easy why he memorized the
driver's manual in like a week and then
he got 100 on the test okay uh the
driver's driving test was a different
thing but uh so it's good to have the
manual in your head and then you can
just pull it up you can say oh I'm
having a problem what problem problem
number one
okay so you can relax nle let's go over
problem number one I hope I I hope it's
okay to throw at you pieces of the nine
and pieces of the six okay so
don't by the end of the week you should
be able to say oh nine goes in between
problem you know and this power and that
level is happening okay you should be
able to do that by the end of the week
not right now okay I'm just throwing out
things to you
um but like given where the Monk Is we
better talk
about the purpose of of TBA okay so TBA
or bringing the Mind back to the
object is required
because the first of the let's go over
the first of the classical problems of
meditation what what's the first problem
you will encounter when you decide to
become a meditator Le yeah say
Leo it's the only Tibetan word that
sounds like the English lay
low and it means laziness okay
uh I prefer to to translate it as not
feeling like meditating okay that's
different right
maybe they're the same in the end but I
don't feel like doing my yoga today is
probably the same as laziness right uh
but it sounds better uh so it's just
this thing you know like you're not
being evil or bad you just don't feel
like it you know so Leo problem number
one of meditation classic problem number
one is I I just don't feel like it today
you know i' rather do something else
today okay
uh so that's the that's the first
problem uh how do you and that has four
Corrections and that why that's why
there's more Corrections than problems
okay cuz number one has three extra
Corrections say
de Shin
sh DBA d
sh those are the four Corrections for Le
I like that what it
Le you got me on my
KNE okay it brings you on your knees
okay uh so what's DEA DEA what is Dea
sh that's why they call guru's grandson
corrupted his name what they call
him sh it's
sh okay his real name is sh sh means
what fath faith okay it's related to her
heart which is heart yeah they come from
the same root okay so faith means heart
like
her heart
Sutra so uh sh
sh faith in
faith in in the high traditions of
ancient India doesn't mean what it means
in English Okay it's a much different
thing sh or faith
means admiring a thing for a bunch of
reasons okay admiring a thing for a
bunch of reasons it's called inet it's
called T ta means
Clarity in the sense of clear water
so the word for faith in tibetan is
clear mountain spring water admiring the
qualities like which implies that you
have a list of qualities in your mind
about why you like something okay so
which are called yens or gunas in
Sanskrit okay so you you have a in your
mind you have a list of stuff you have a
in your mind you have a list list of
cool stuff that you like about something
or somebody okay so sh towards a person
would mean uh let's say towards a
teacher when you have shda in this
tradition in this lineage it should
derive from a mental list of good
qualities that you make about them and
we compared it in the November teachings
to uh falling in love with your high
school boyfriend or girlfriend
so whether you're totally aware of the
process or
not uh when you meet a new girl when
you're 16 or 18 or
whatever uh you are making lists of
things you like you know in your mind
you are making lists you know like I
like her hair I like the way she dresses
I like the music she listens to you know
stuff like that
Etc and and usually the more things on
the list the stronger the faith will be
you see and the more lasting it will be
if you base a relationship with somebody
on one or two
qualities uh it's very likely to change
okay so normally sh good good sh strong
sh should be a ever expanding list of
cool stuff that you notice about
somebody or something okay in this case
what meditating meditating okay just
meditating okay so the very first
antidote to not feeling like meditating
is to sit down and make mental lists
about
about the cool stuff that's going to
happen to you if you meditate all right
so
that's you do it automatically with a
girl you do it automatically with your
food
uh you do it quite naturally with your
enemies people you don't like you're
constantly making
lists of things you don't like about
them okay like if I ask you who's the
person who most irritates you you could
say so and so and then if I said why you
would have at least
10 immediately
recollect
uh anti qualities or you know things
that bother you about them because you
have meditated on
them because you have allowed that to
take over your mind and youve reviewed
it constantly and now you have a nice
solid list of 5 to 10 top irritating
things about them and you can tell whole
stories about them to people you know
like 20 minute accounts of some harm
they have done you or something
irritating about them so now try to do
it with meditation you see try to do it
with
your with think about meditation if you
can't name 10 reasons to meditate off
the top of your head quickly at any
given time you will you won't meditate
you'll get Lelo okay so you should be
able in your own mind to
call up reasons why you're meditating
okay in the same way it's not difficult
to call up reasons why you're in love
right
uh let me let me count the way right so
with your meditation it should be let me
count the way okay
what people give me some things just
raise your hand and I'll call on you and
give me some reasons to meditate just
just off the top of your head no raise
your hand okay okay
Dary yeah I mean we kind of uh what do
you call it we tend to talk down as of
of that as a reason but it it is it does
make you Comm and peaceful okay it makes
you Comm and
peaceful Insight yeah it makes you it
easier to
uh crack spiritual problems or go to
deeper perceptions of things yeah sh
mind yeah just in general if you
meditate
regularly properly your mind is Con is
really sharper than other people so like
uh Michael Gordon if those of you who
know him I mean he made a $50 million
company uh was bought by a stale out
there I
think and I asked him one day you know
why why do you think and he said well I
just had my mind is faster and I say why
and he said said gu I learned TM when I
was 18 or something Transcendental
Meditation which I think is sort of
like I don't know the Gumby of
meditations but uh oh I'm sorry it's
SpongeBob now what are we up
to we haven't gone past SpongeBob are
you sure you're not just having an older
child no there is no there's those uh
those rubber band things
that the parents have to pay
for plain old rubber bands with a Twist
in them that are somehow extremely
significant okay she's got yeah
okay I wish I had the company that men
anyway why did I mention that oh yeah TM
with that but anyway he never stopped
like it's my boss used to talk about
this guy they found in uima 30 years
later still defending one of the
caves you
know his rifle was all rusted away and
nobody ever told him to stop you know
and he was ready to kill somebody who
walked in the cave and
uh why don't talk about
that oh yeah so he never stopped his
DM like everybody else stopped they
called it off and he didn't get the
message and uh he did five minutes of
rubber band
meditation and it worked okay his mind
became extremely sharp for business okay
yeah next stop suffering say stop
suffering yeah stop suffering uh that's
a good reason to to do anything is that
uh if you become
a a good person not even a Buddha I
think just if you become a good examp
example uh it will
proliferate people will see you and
they'll say I I would like that
also I gave the Harry metal example in
in mainland China and I I was I was
sternly told afterwards that that that
wasn't appropriate for a Chinese
artist apparently a monk is not supposed
to get up and make orgasm
sounds in China okay anyway all right
a sense of peaceful oh do you know the
Harry and
Sally Harry me Sally for the one person
who didn't hear that
story
uh I didn't see the movie I just saw
that section from it and uh in some I
don't know Academy Awards thing but
anyway they were
uh apparently the Guy meets The girl and
they go out to dinner and then they're
having a quiet dinner in a very
expensive
restaurant and uh for some reason the
lady goes into uh orgasm and making
those sounds okay they sitting at the
table he's not touching you he's sitting
across the table and then
uh some very wealthy lady walks in with
a white suit and gold chains and you
know and uh she sits down and she's like
everybody in the restaurant is like
staring at them and she sits down she
stares at them them and then the waiter
is over here standing there waiting for
her with this towel and the menu you
know and then finally he like hits her
on the
shoulder what you know and uh he says
Madame you know here's the menu what
what would you like to have and she
doesn't take her eyes off of I guess
it's Sally I don't know for sure but she
says I'll have what she's
having okay
so uh with
meditation it's that uh if you seem to
be happy if you seem to be unusually
happy or unusually successful I mean
somebody come up to Michael Gordon and
say what what happened you know and then
he'll say or you'll say I meditate every
day and it makes me really happy and
then we always talk about bodh CH is
some ideal you know like some bodh CH
somehow you're going to get bodh CH and
then somehow it's going to save the
world
uh but it's more likely to happen that
you just seem very happy person and you
seem to be very contented and satisfied
and and concentrated and and tender
towards people and then people will ask
you what are you doing now I'll have
what she's having you see I mean they
they'll say whatever you're doing I want
I want to know what you're doing okay so
there's the what do you call I think
there's this new model of bod
that that you are so happy that other
people get attracted to you and then
they ask what you're doing and you say
I'm meditating and then you say you got
to know all you got to know is the nine
the six the four the eight the
five so yeah another one another
reason power
of yeah he said it makes the power of
your good deeds stronger and I think
that relates to uh you know we're
undertaking
a
10-year Journey Through the L through
the steps to Enlightenment
so uh the selling point that Pabon gives
for meditation is that it will enable
you to succeed at each of the steps okay
at each of the realiz realizations are
called LBA okay L Rim so L RM refers to
a book a genre of literature but L RM
also means
each of those realizations that you need
to it's those are like small Mount
Everest that you have to climb to get to
the goal
so he when he sells meditation in the
book he says if you learn to meditate
well then when you get to death
meditation you you have the instrument
is ready and then when you get to
Leisure and Fortune the instrument is
ready and then when you get to the
Perfections the instrument is ready so
it's an instrument that will be applied
to each of the L that you go
through next that
all you can work at the planetary level
and you can see patterns 500 years out
yeah yeah she said you could work at a
planetarian level and see patterns 500
years which is called mun okay say
mun uh AB which means
uh the
ability it means what do you call
Miracle Powers cities and these are
considered
uh
lesser uh but they're cons that that
they're important okay for example the
ability to read other people's
minds which is particularly useful in a
bar or I'm just kidding I the only time
I've ever been to a bar was when my bus
broke down outside a bar uh on the way
to New Jersey but uh
but uh but also useful when you're
trying to help people you see because
then you know you know what's wrong with
them you know you know what they need
you can read their mind and know what
they need okay so that's one city we
could just start listing cities right
you can
fly uh very I think useful you can see
the future okay and it doesn't
start in connection with seeing
emptiness directly it it's direct you
see events 500 years out for
example but on a daytoday level it's uh
intimations of what's going to happen
which allow you to act in in ways which
are more successful in your life so you
have intimations or hints or feelings
about what's going to happen and they're
true and you don't even notice it you
just act on them you're acting about a
month ahead of other people or a week
ahead of other people and you may not
even be conscious of it and you're just
more successful than other people
because you're
actually getting incomplete pictures of
of what's going to happen so you know
you invest in a certain stock or you or
you hire a certain person or you take a
certain uh Retreat camp or stuff like
that just you you make people say oh
they seem to make the Right Moves
but it's it's and you may not even
realize why you're doing it and it's
because you have a
slight developing a slight abis a slight
Clairvoyance so those
are all of those depend on meditation
and they are
not even just to be a good baseball
player the the to know where the ball's
going to come somehow or to make the
right move or in the military or stuff
you just know what's coming next next
and you do the right thing uh okay next
none one yeah have any
progress you won't have any spiritual
progress if you won't
meditate yeah if you're talking about
the five levels of the five
paths which are expressed in a
famous scripture from China in a certain
Mantra J
which is gy gy right so uh what Chelsea
is saying is that uh to move up to the
five levels of Spiritual Development the
classic levels that the Buddha talked
about which we're not getting into here
uh you must be in a state of meditation
you cannot move from one level to
another unless you are at level n
level eight or something like that you
can't progress it's not possible you
only get what do you call used to say
graduated promoted he used to say you
only get promoted you know if you are in
deep meditation you can't move between
levels unless you're in deep medit so
it's not possible for you to go higher
than you are now unless you can reach
deep meditation like level eight or
level n something like that okay I don't
I'm pretty disappointed in this list
yeah
tring yeah more single pointed in all
aspects of
life I would say along with that in my
mind the ability to really enjoy a thing
you see because we tend
to Americans seek to enjoyment in
quantity or in uh the number of events
the number of you can undertake right
and and I think rather we don't have our
capacity as much as some other countries
to like in the in France I used to think
of French
people uh I I I thought they were just
too hung up on food and that it was a
bad thing and that they probably ate all
day and you know and then I got to
France and I sat down for a meal and I
was on my laptop it was in Paris on
Walmart and
and I pulled out my laptop and the
waiter like looks at me and he's like
you know M this is a restaurant you know
and you can't taste the food you know
like put the laptop away and then I
ordered a meal and he comes out with a
big plate with two asparagus is on it
you know and I'm like I thought this is
the country who everybody ate you know
and then he's like but you and then he
went into this long explanation of why
you have to focus on the taste of the
asparagus and you chew it slowly and you
taste it and you take time and you taste
it and and and it came out that he
expected me to stay in the restaurant
for at least 2
hours no and he was serious he said you
you you can't enjoy the thing unless you
give it some time and you give it some
attention you know and and then I
realized they don't overeat they just
enjoy because they're focused on it you
know and they they what do you call they
they like get the most out eating two
pieces of asparagus somehow they see 14
different experiences in there and it
and it's really happening and that
happened all over France we were in I
forget the name of the
town
anyway it was the same thing uh
explaining why this garlic soup had 18
flavors in it and then it really was
there but an American would just gobble
you know the Americans are like
Pringle
you all kind of
Pringles and then it play a French F you
know like that and
uh so yeah it's single point what I'm
saying is that the capacity of being
concentrated allows a much more
enjoyment of life you know just to be
able to concentrate on anything for an
extended period is allows your deeper
enjoyment of everything right okay
anything yeah
stop that's a one she said stop death
and create a blissful
Paradise yeah but
what because you see emptiness I mean
nobody said that yet okay I mean that's
number one you can't see emptiness
directly if you don't get to love of
mind it's not possible it will never
happen you can not stop your jealousy
anger
desire other negative states of mind you
cannot help other people really unless
you see emptiness directly you cannot
you are excluded from that experience
forever if you can't get to level n okay
so that and there's other levels the
that's not the end of
concentration uh there are seven higher
levels of concentration
uh Beyond level 9ine but we don't need
to go there uh level 9 is enough to see
emptiness and then you can stop there
cuz
that's that's like making a telescope
that can see I don't know you don't need
a hub telescope to kill a deer you know
they exist those levels exist but
they're not meaningful if all you want
to do is shoot a deer you just need a
certain scope you know and that's enough
so
that's the big reason right any more
I'll do one or two more yeah Med
actually prove day yeah if you meditate
in the
morning
uh you you you you change the rest of
the day okay the the act of meditation
changes the rest of the day couple of
reasons okay one is that you're working
at the core of the mind when you
meditate deeply you're not really in
your head okay you're the Mig you're in
the you're in the tiny space within your
heart chakra from which the world is
Flowing so if you meditate every day at
that place then that actually changes
the events of the day it's like that
movie what's that movie uh Groundhog Day
is
it is it I didn't see it I heard about
it it they go through the day again yeah
but it happens differently or something
like he goes through six different
versions of the same day or
something
and oh that isn't what I thought it was
then uh I was thinking more like a movie
where uh the character does a small
different thing at oh okay yeah early in
the day and then the and then later in
the day the whole day changes or those
movies where people come from the future
and they say we're going to shoot you if
you touch anything cuz then Napoleon
won't be born and Lincoln won't have a
chance and you know like that so if you
meditate in the morning somebody told me
you have to talk to Americans in terms
of films because that's the only thing
that's real to them uh so uh anyway uh
now they say it's true I saw in a
movie uh so anyway
uh where were we oh yeah you can change
the whole day you change the way the day
flows by meditating at the core of the
heart chakra which is where you are when
you're
concentrating uh you what do you call it
you you change the course of the history
for the day the day will happen
differently because you're fing around
at the seed core okay
there was something else there I don't
remember what else did you say change
the day Thea oh the karma for the day
yeah I don't
know oh yeah I wanted to say one more
thing
uh D I think it's called do I I can't
quite remember I think it's
called here's an interesting thing for
you to think
about if you spend a half hour in
meditation in the
morning uh you won't have time to argue
with somebody during that half
hour there's a whole theory of Buddhist
Meditation that says uh the reason it's
so cool is that you don't have time to
do all your normal bad Deeds while
you're meditating like you can't kill
anybody while you're meditating you
can't lie to anybody while you're
meditating anytime you talk we we
learned that after the last three-year
treat the minute you start talking you
start lying or or you start exaggerating
in my
case but uh we almost can't speak
without making some kind
of you know small lines small
exaggerations and then uh if you sit
quietly without talking for half hour
you miss
that you've got so
23.5 / 24 is about 2 and 12% or
something anyway you you get a a
little your day will go better because
you got 2 and a half% less Bad Karma
than you would have had if you hadn't
stayed silent for half an hour okay one
more you get a kind of uh spaciousness
where you can consider what you think
about what you're learning and it seems
to apply into all the events of the day
so you can become a considered person
rather
than yeah I I think you get more
introspective yeah and
uh you learn to watch the state of your
own mind right so then it's it's a lot
better if you start to get angry or or
things like that your own mind is you
learn to watch your own mind most
people why is why is consciousness the
fifth
G and why is colors and shapes the fris
G you know physical stuff they in the
scripture they say it's because of ease
of
observation like feelings are lower than
Consciousness because it's not hard to
be aware how you feel it's easiest to be
aware of colors and shame it's it's it's
fairly easy to be aware of how you feel
but it's rare to find a person who's
reflecting on the fact that they are
conscious you see you take Consciousness
for granted you are aware you are not
dead you are not a log you are not a
stone you have Consciousness you are
right now you're
aware that's a tremendous Karma
extremely rare Karma and you have
awareness you have awareness of the
world to be aware of your awareness is
very rare among people if you're
meditating you you can do it okay you're
aware of the state of your own mind and
then you can fix your mind but most
people aren't even aware of their mind
they're just in it all right so I'm
going to push a little more I hope you
don't mind what were we supposed to do
we were supposed to have dinner huh we
were supposed to have dinner at what
time 20 minutes 20 minutes ago they're
probably running late anyway they're
probably running
late uh okay we'll go another 5 minutes
um so we just we just addressed the
first of the
eight Corrections the antidotes okay we
were talking about making
lists we were talking about making lists
of why it would be cool to meditate okay
and and those got to be in your mind at
any given time you know like somebody
come up to you and say why do you like
Maple covered donuts and you say well
there's the the crunchy part there's the
Slick part there's the it's a little
bite of the maple taste and you know you
got to be able to do it with meditation
or you won't meditate
so conversely if you find yourself
avoiding meditation you might want
to do a little meditation on uh how good
it is to meditate or all the benefits of
got it if you find yourself not feeling
like meditating review the benefits of
it that's the classic antidote for the
the first of the four antidotes for the
first problem
DEA uh which which leads automatically
to Dumba which is the
second uh fix for the first problem
which is
what desire want yeah you want it you
want it you see if
you going back to the high school
girlfriend analogy you you make a list
of how cool she is how she listens to
the right music you know all the cool
things about her and then what does that
trigger
desire to ask her out I mean I'm talking
High School like you're scared you know
and then but you got all these sooner or
later the list overcomes the this being
scared and you're just compelled to ask
her out you know even if you're going to
get you know what do you call it blown
off uh because you've been making a list
uh you're inspired to try you know you
try Dumba means I want I want
it you know I want it try
it say
again means what yeah you then you move
you move so what means you move you do
something okay you do something you ask
her out okay you check you you you keep
seeing her and making listen your mind
more and more list in your mind until it
reaches a what do you call
Watershed thresold level and and that
drives you to want her and then the
wanting drives you to take the risk and
you move you say something you do
something okay so t
means
uh if you want those meditation things
bad enough you will get on the cushion
it means get on the cushion okay you
will get on the cushion okay you'll sit
down and get on the cushion okay that's
Sil
you got few more minutes what's
shinjang shinjang means you get really
good at it you just get really good at
it shinjang okay mentally and physically
it's always divided into mental Shin
Jang and physical Shang your body you
you sit down to meditate and it just
clip you know your hands come down on
your knees and physically there's just
this clip you're in the groove shinjang
means in the groove shinjang means in
the groove like yoga if you do yoga a
lot I get a lot of what do you call
sinus
congestion and there's something about
the yoga it opens up some kind of
Channel that I get a discharge of
uh what do you call is there a polite
word not uh no it used to take maybe 45
minutes and and yesterday I did half a
sunsai attention and it all came out
you know like that what used to take 45
minutes came out in in in the on the one
side of a sun scienti and uh that's
shinjang okay so shinjang means you're
just
physically in the groove the minute you
start and then
mentally you're mentally you're deep
within a few seconds and you're pretty
you guys are good I felt it in the room
people in China are awesome I don't know
why I I don't know China and Taiwan
they're awesome I think it's thousands
of years of despite all the recent
political things there's a there's
something there and you say let's
meditate and then a thousand people are
just totally silent and no nobody's even
like sniffling or anything and it's
weird uh in a prison also high security
what do you call Max maximum 20 years to
life for us they they have the same
feeling you know you say let's meditate
this curtain comes boom that's Shin Jang
okay so that those are the four
paradoxically you don't get to shinjang
till the end of the process right so you
know I've been studying some scriptures
of
why how do you
put how does antidote number four come
to a person who's just starting to
meditate and then the scripture says
well
relatively okay like you don't really
get to number four until much later
meditation doesn't become High enjoyment
until later
okay it doesn't become Blissful until
later but it certainly prevents
Leo okay so real shinjang might take a
while uh but it certainly stops you from
what do you call it that resistance to
you could call Leo as a resistance to
meditate okay right all right so we got
the first of the five problems we got
the first four of the eight antidotes
we're up to the second of the nine
levels we've talked
about the we didn't talk about the first
of the six powers and we don't have any
of the states of mind yet are you with
me yes then you get to have
dinner
uh okay all right